<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Projects | Kamranicus]]></title>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/categories/projects/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-05T03:41:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://kamranicus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kamran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Behind the Major Update to Keep Track of My Games]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/30/ktomg-update/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-30T22:13:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/30/ktomg-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7899619/b3154994-072a-11e5-8da1-b9a9703a8b57.png" alt="My profile" /></p>

<p>Today I just pushed a <strong>major</strong> update to <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com">KTOMG</a>. <em>Psst, you should join!</em></p>

<p>You can <a href="http://blog.keeptrackofmygames.com/post/120264549011/updates-for-may-2015">reference the blog post</a> for details on features but on the technical side I&rsquo;m pretty proud because I got to implement a bunch of new tech that I&rsquo;ve been wanting to learn properly.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h2>At a glance</h2>

<p>The site is built using <a href="http://getbootstrap.com">Bootstrap</a>, <a href="http://lesscss.org">LESS</a>, and <a href="http://knockoutjs.com">Knockout.js</a>. It is totally responsive and yes, every feature is available on every view. I don&rsquo;t yet have offline mode or some more app-y things like local storage quite yet but it&rsquo;s on my to-do list. By far the hardest thing to make responsive was the list view but using Flexbox and toolbar configurations, it&rsquo;s manageable. It could always be simpler though, my work is never done.</p>

<h2>CSS3 Flexbox</h2>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7899652/94500830-072c-11e5-8656-59fb097ecf36.png" alt="Lists" /></p>

<p>The list view is using <a href="https://css-tricks.com/snippets/css/a-guide-to-flexbox/">CSS3 Flexbox</a> with <code>display: table</code> fallback w/JavaScript. A Flexbox grid is perfect for a modern responsive app, which KTOMG is. It scales down to mobile fine (and if you don&rsquo;t have Flexbox or if the fallback fails, the worst you get is a stacked list). For different breakpoints I customize the flex basis of the items to create 1-3 column layouts. The homepage will soon use Flexbox as soon as I get to it (right now it&rsquo;s using <code>display: table</code> to maintain equal-height columns). All of the modern browsers support Flexbox and for those that don&rsquo;t, they just get a wrapping grid.</p>

<p>I also use Flexbox for any grid of games using table display as a fallback; this prevents me from needing to have fixed column sizes for different screen sizes so the games will just wrap as they need to.</p>

<p><strong>Aside:</strong> The box art image grid for the list is simply just the first four games in the list (dynamically updated, since the entire page uses Knockout) positioned using <code>background-size</code> and <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/CSS/Using_multiple_backgrounds">multiple backgrounds</a>. It uses a placeholder image repeated 4 times, in case the games are missing artwork and during loading.</p>

<p>Most of the CSS3/HTML5 stuff I have fallbacks by detecting features using <a href="http://modernizr.com/">Modernizr</a>.</p>

<h2>HTML5 Drag and Drop</h2>

<p>The other cool thing Flexbox gives you is some hot drag and drop action by allowing dynamic insertion of flex items:</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7899631/1b7db50c-072b-11e5-9977-49c7b6c3b176.gif" alt="Drag and drop" /></p>

<p>I wrote the drag and drop code in vanilla HTML5 Javascript, it wasn&rsquo;t too bad <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/HTML/Drag_and_drop">using MDN as a guide</a>. The fallback if that isn&rsquo;t supported is simply toolbar icons (which really is faster anyway for moving things far).</p>

<p>I admit I haven&rsquo;t tried a browser that <em>doesn&rsquo;t</em> support Flexbox but <em>does</em> support drag/drop, so that case might still need some tweaking.</p>

<h2>Hopscotch Tutorials</h2>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7899658/bda3d91e-072c-11e5-80ea-932d2f309681.png" alt="Tutorials" /></p>

<p>Since lists are pretty powerful, people might need some help remembering all the things they can do.</p>

<p>I use a modified version of <a href="http://linkedin.github.io/hopscotch">Hopscotch</a> for an introduction tutorial. I struggled at first to figure out how I wanted to do tutorials. I ended up just using a string array on every user that I fill in when they finish a tutorial, allowing for an infinite number of tutorials and everyone not seeing them by default. I keep a master list of valid tutorials on the server.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a simple solution that will let me add tutorials as I can make them. It took me a little finnagling, but I also got the tour working fine on small screens.</p>

<h2>Stats with Chart.js</h2>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7899666/222e5d5a-072d-11e5-9328-f52ae59c9e76.png" alt="Stats" /></p>

<p>I use <a href="http://www.chartjs.org/">Chart.js</a> for profile and list stats. The API is easy to use and easy to extend, as well as being sufficiently sexy. The stats I show right now are just the tip of the iceberg. I look forward to generating some cool charts later on (especially the Radar ones for comparisons).</p>

<p>Also, I apparently really like Action/Adventure and RPGs. But I knew that already, tell me something I don&rsquo;t know! Like maybe my &ldquo;burndown&rdquo; for finishing my backlog&hellip;</p>

<h2>I&rsquo;m excited</h2>

<p>I worked on this update all month as my wife will attest. I still have <a href="ktomg.uservoice.com/">plenty</a> to do but <a href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/21/5-things-for-6-months-abroad/">our vacation</a> is coming to an end. I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;ll be able to release such massive updates each month but this one definitely gets me closer to completing the vision I have. I&rsquo;m pretty excited! The updates are just in time for the big gaming conferences, if only I could get public lists out by the end of June&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
