<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Year in Review | Kamranicus]]></title>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/categories/year-in-review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-11T01:05:59+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://kamranicus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kamran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2015: A Year in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2016/01/05/year-in-review/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-05T01:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2016/01/05/year-in-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2015 was a very eventful (and fulfilling) year for me and my wife. Let&rsquo;s break it down, shall we?</p>

<h2>Living abroad for 6 months</h2>

<p><img src="https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/2000/1*-h8wTj1iOSrHHtnGMxR60w.jpeg" alt="Bordeaux, France" /></p>

<p>By far the most impressive thing I did last year was to <a href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/21/5-things-for-6-months-abroad/">take a 6 month sabbatical</a> and live abroad in France with my wife. Though I&rsquo;ve written about it previously, I left out the entire part where we chronicled our adventure in a series of publications on <a href="http://medium.com">Medium</a>. We kept it anonymous during the trip to avoid any potential issues but now that it&rsquo;s over, I will list the different publications so you can read back through what we did for 6 months (spoiler: we did <em>a lot</em>).</p>

<p>Just to be clear when you&rsquo;re reading, I am <strong>Vincent</strong> and my wife is <strong>Celeste.</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/visa-vis-a-guide">Visa-Vis: A Guide</a> &ndash; Prologue series of posts on steps to being able to live in France for 6 months</li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/aix-squared">Aix Squared</a> &ndash; Dec 23, 2015-June 14, 2015 &ndash; General posts on food, cities, and living in France</li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/aix-squared/rennes-france-d4957bf17d4e">Rennes</a>, <a href="https://medium.com/aix-squared/nantes-france-5c0aa9cf5ff">Nantes</a>, <a href="https://medium.com/aix-squared/bordeaux-france-c66f859826c9">Bordeaux</a> &ndash; April 24-30, 2015 &ndash; A tour of north/western France</li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/aix-in-amsterdam">Aix in Amsterdam</a> &ndash; February 11-19, 2015</li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/aix-in-marrakesh">Aix in Marrakesh</a> &ndash; March 10-16, 2015</li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/aix-in-dublin">Aix in Dublin</a> &ndash; April 5-9, 2015</li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/aix-in-oslo">Aix in Oslo</a> &ndash; April 9-13, 2015</li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/aix-in-london">Aix in London</a> &ndash; May 12-16, 2015</li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/aix-in-florence">Aix in Florence</a> &ndash; June 9-14, 2015</li>
</ul>


<p>It was an experience I&rsquo;ll never forget and one that probably won&rsquo;t be repeated anytime soon. My wife and I both felt it was the right time and that we&rsquo;d probably get little to no chance at doing something so crazy once we had kids and &ldquo;settled down.&rdquo; We still hope to continue traveling once a year or couple years, especially after an experience like that. One of my plans for 2016 is to compile all these posts into a book that we print and keep for us and our future children.</p>

<h2>New House</h2>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/12107000/cd7f12cc-b32a-11e5-852e-78b839331383.png" alt="Bay window" /></p>

<p>We weren&rsquo;t in a position to buy a house so soon after a 6 month sabbatical but we still thought it was best to move from apartment living to a real house, especially after living in a 400 sq ft space in France. We found a great place to rent in Minneapolis that&rsquo;s pretty close to both workplaces, friends, and family. We&rsquo;ve done a few things to it to make it more like home and we&rsquo;ve been really enjoying it so far and our landlord is superb. The photo above is our enhancement to the bay window. My brother-in-law built the spanning bench between the bookcases and I built the cushion. I removed the tall blinds that covered the window so we could open up the room and add extra seating. It turned out so good!</p>

<h2>New Dog</h2>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/12107029/1b61acac-b32b-11e5-9bee-3325f44374db.png" alt="Dogger" /></p>

<p>My wife has always wanted a dog ever since we moved into an apartment together&mdash;except our apartment complex never let us have dogs. We cat-sat (is that a word?) for 2 years for some friends and then they took her back down to Texas where they bought a house and she happily frolicks outside. In August (Dogust?) we went to the humane society and on pretty-much-a-whim took in a cute dog we named Rennes (after <a href="https://medium.com/aix-squared/rennes-france-d4957bf17d4e">one of our favorite French cities</a> we visited). She&rsquo;s a black lab and border collie mix. She&rsquo;s awesome even though she jumps the fence to chase squirrels (we&rsquo;re working on that). We love her a ton.</p>

<h2>Keep Track of My Games</h2>

<p><img src="http://41.media.tumblr.com/fe33ac3443fbfeab5b2e4da2c6fe170e/tumblr_inline_nyz1izCCVg1qlpzxk_500.png" alt="KTOMG" /></p>

<p>2015 marked the <a href="http://blog.keeptrackofmygames.com/post/124929587854/happy-4th-birthday-to-keep-track-of-my-games">4th year</a> that <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com">KTOMG</a> has been around since its humble beginnings and while I was abroad it gave me time to focus and finish a <a href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/30/ktomg-update/">major rewrite of the codebase in May</a>. Since then I&rsquo;ve released <a href="http://blog.keeptrackofmygames.com/post/134750555276/updates-for-november-2015">public lists</a> and capping the year off with <a href="http://blog.keeptrackofmygames.com/post/135781123861/updates-for-december-2015">Steam syncing</a>, just to name a few features.</p>

<h2>Speaking</h2>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kb7tvaBJeMs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Even though I was abroad for 6 months, I still managed to give a talk this year at Twin Cities Code Camp 19: an update to my popular <a href="http://kamranicus.com/presentations/demystifying-typescript">Demystifying TypeScript</a> presentation. You can also find 2014&rsquo;s version <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kb7tvaBJeMs">on YouTube</a>.</p>

<h2>Making Games</h2>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/12107063/7b1593c0-b32b-11e5-9148-0470e84acfb4.png" alt="Minotaur" /></p>

<p>In August, I participated in the <a href="http://ludumdare.com/compo/ludum-dare-33/">Ludum Dare 33</a> game jam where some friends and I created a minotaur hack-n-slash game, <a href="http://excaliburjs.com/ludum-33/">Crypt of the Minotaur</a> (<a href="https://github.com/excaliburjs/ludum-33">source</a>). I love participating in game jams and by extension, helping to contribute to the <a href="http://excaliburjs.com">Excalibur.js</a> game engine.</p>

<h2>Playing Games</h2>

<p>Somehow after all that I still managed to log hundreds of hours into my gaming habit. Since I added public lists to KTOMG, why don&rsquo;t you go take a look at my <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com/users/kamranicus/lists/11">Top 10 Played Games of 2015</a>? Yes, some of those came out in 2014 but I didn&rsquo;t play or finish them until this year. Being abroad, I managed to bring my laptop, 3DS, and PS4 so I played a lot of <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com/games/1931">Destiny</a>, finished the remastered <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com/games/394">Grim Fandango</a> and other PS4/3DS games. My laptop wasn&rsquo;t that great but I was able to still enjoy <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com/games/1267">Pillars of Eternity</a>, a throwback Baldur&rsquo;s Gate-style RPG. In November, I started playing <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com/games/145171">Fallout 4</a> and have since logged over 75 hours in it. It&rsquo;s definitely tough to juggle both hobbies: playing games and developing a site that helps manage those games. During time off, I usually try to mix my time between them to satisfy both needs and sticking to a monthly release cadence helps a lot to prioritize work.</p>

<h2>Work &amp; Friends</h2>

<p>My work has been going swimmingly, after my sabbatical I returned to work on a team with one of my best friends. Speaking of friends, I made more this year, fulfilling a goal I made at the start of 2015&mdash;not only abroad but also at home. Board game nights, Dungeon World sessions, and a Star Wars marathon are just some of the highlights of the fun stuff we&rsquo;ve done with our [awesome] circle of friends.</p>

<h2>Looking towards a new year</h2>

<p>Cheers to 2016, let&rsquo;s hope it&rsquo;s even bigger and better than 2015 and brings more happiness and joy to my life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
