<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: CI | Kamranicus]]></title>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/categories/ci/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-29T01:34:52+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://kamranicus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kamran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Triggering a Travis Build Programmatically]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/03/29/triggering-a-travis-build-programmatically/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-29T22:45:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/03/29/triggering-a-travis-build-programmatically</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For <a href="http://excaliburjs.com">Exalibur.js</a> we wanted to be able to keep our <code>master</code> branch documentation up-to-date on the website. The website is built using <a href="http://assemble.io">Assemble.io</a> and GitHub pages and <a href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/02/26/continuous-deployment-with-travis-ci/">after successfully automating my blog</a>, naturally I turned to <a href="http://travis-ci.org">Travis CI</a> to set up automated documentation generation.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>Travis normally sets up a hook in your GitHub repository to automatically trigger a build after you push a commit (or pull request). This is real nice but unfortunately that&rsquo;s where it stops. If you want to trigger a build <strong>for another repository</strong>, you have to do it manually.</p>

<p>I asked Travis about this and their response is promising (Twitter can be nice sometimes):</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/kamranayub">@kamranayub</a> it&#39;s on the roadmap, and hopefully landing soon &lt;3</p>&mdash; Travis CI (@travisci) <a href="https://twitter.com/travisci/status/582311038772723713">March 29, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://kamranicus.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Until that time, though, something has to be done.</p>

<p>One approach I saw was a <a href="https://github.com/metaodi/travis-ping">small Ruby script</a> to forge a webhook POST message. This is actually a nice idea but since Excalibur uses Node to build, I needed something else and didn&rsquo;t want to port it over.</p>

<p>Instead I borrowed some code from <a href="https://github.com/patrickkettner/travis-ping">@patrickketner</a> that uses the <a href="https://github.com/pwmckenna/node-travis-ci">node-travis-ci</a> npm package to submit a build through the public API. I modified Patrick&rsquo;s code since I need to use GitHub personal access tokens like I did <a href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/02/26/continuous-deployment-with-travis-ci/">previously</a>.</p>

<p>You still need to follow the same steps to set up the <code>GH_TOKEN</code> environment variable but once you do, all you have to do is execute this Node.js script (changing the <code>repo</code>).</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/kamranayub/88f963a9ac3d5bf6114d.js"></script>


<p>So for example, in your <code>.travis.yml</code> file, you just need:</p>

<p><code>
install:
  - npm install travis-ci
after_success:
  - node trigger-build.js
</code></p>

<p>All set. Now when you commit to one repository, you can trigger a build for another one. This allows us to automatically <a href="http://excaliburjs.com/docs/api/edge">keep our docs up-to-date</a> with whatever <code>master</code> has.</p>

<p>You can <a href="https://github.com/excaliburjs/Excalibur/blob/master/deploy-docs.js">reference Excalibur</a> to see how we execute the script. Additionally, you can reference <a href="https://github.com/excaliburjs/excaliburjs.github.io/blob/site/.travis.yml">excaliburjs.com&rsquo;s Travis configuration</a> to see how we use <a href="http://typedoc.io">TypeDoc</a> to generate documentation for the latest version of <code>master</code>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continuous Deployment With Travis-CI]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/02/26/continuous-deployment-with-travis-ci/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-26T16:18:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/02/26/continuous-deployment-with-travis-ci</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the fun things we did for <a href="http://playsweepstacks.com">Sweep Stacks</a> (our Ludum Dare entry)
during development was to setup continuous deployment. Since our GitHub
repository was public, we could leverage the excellent Travis CI build tool.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>This allowed us to work on the game and have our dedicated tester play every new build
hot off the press. It reduced the amount of bugs we shipped with and created a very
fast feedback loop for QA. In the end it allowed us to push a polished game an hour
or so before the deadline hit. After the voting began, it also allowed us to quickly
push bug fixes that were reported by players.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re new to Travis CI, you can learn more about what it is and
how to get started by reading <a href="http://tech.pro/tutorial/1749/get-your-ci-on-with-travis-ci">my Tech.pro tutorial</a>.</p>

<p>Once you have your project building, you can then write a little bash script to
deploy it! By &ldquo;deploying&rdquo;, what I really mean is pushing your built code to your production branch on GitHub for final deployment. For example, we use GitHub pages to host Sweep Stacks.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s look at the process.</p>

<h2>Customizing Travis Config</h2>

<p>You will need to execute a script to deploy your site, so you will need to
customize your <strong>_travis.yml</strong> file.</p>

<p>Here is what mine looks like for this blog (built using Octopress):</p>

<pre><code>language: ruby
rvm:
  - 1.9.3
branches:
  only:
    - source
env:
  global:
  - GH_REF: github.com/kamranayub/kamranayub.github.io.git
script:
  - bundle exec rake generate
  - chmod ugo+x deploy.sh
  - '[ "${TRAVIS_PULL_REQUEST}" != "false" ] || ./deploy.sh'
</code></pre>

<p>Let&rsquo;s break it down:</p>

<pre><code>language: ruby
</code></pre>

<p>Easy, since I use <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> (built on Jekyll) for my blog, we need to use Ruby.</p>

<pre><code>rvm:
  - 1.9.3
</code></pre>

<p>The version of Octopress I use requires Ruby 1.9.3.</p>

<pre><code>branches:
  only:
    - source
</code></pre>

<p>We only want Travis to initiate builds for the <code>source</code> branch, since that is where
the source files are for my blog.</p>

<pre><code>env:
  global:
  - GH_REF: github.com/kamranayub/kamranayub.github.io.git
</code></pre>

<p>We will need to be able to clone and push to our repository, so we store it in an
environment variable for easy access. <code>GH_REF</code> will be available to our bash script.</p>

<pre><code>script:
  - bundle exec rake generate
  - chmod ugo+x deploy.sh
  - '[ "${TRAVIS_PULL_REQUEST}" != "false" ] || ./deploy.sh''
</code></pre>

<p>In our Travis script, we build the blog (<code>rake generate</code>). We then mark our <code>deploy.sh</code> file
as executable (since I&rsquo;m on Windows). After that we execute our deploy as long as this isn&rsquo;t
a pull request (don&rsquo;t want to build other people&rsquo;s changes!). Disabling pull request builds
can also be set in your Travis project settings.</p>

<h2>Deploy script</h2>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the script I use to do the deployment:</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/kamranayub/ca7b6866ab43771d9da8.js"></script>


<p>As you can see it&rsquo;s fairly simple. One thing to make sure of is hiding your access token (<code>GH_TOKEN</code>),
we use to authenticate which I&rsquo;ll show you how to generate and use.</p>

<h2>The access token</h2>

<p>The whole reason this works is because we are authenticating to GitHub using a <em>Personal
Access Token</em> (stored in <code>GH_TOKEN</code>). This is an OAuth token that you can create when
using Two-Factor Auth to authenticate 3rd party tools like Visual Studio, or in our case, authenticating in a script.</p>

<p>You can generate a token by:</p>

<ol>
<li>Going to <a href="https://github.com/settings/applications">Applications</a> in your Settings</li>
<li>Clicking &ldquo;Generate New Token&rdquo;</li>
<li>Selecting your permissions (for Travis, all you need is <code>public_repo</code>)</li>
<li>Once created, copy the token to your clipboard (you <em>must</em> regenerate it if you lose it)</li>
</ol>


<p>Now we need to configure Travis to expose this token securely to our script.</p>

<ol>
<li>On Travis, go to the Settings of your project (top-right)</li>
<li>Click the &ldquo;Environment Variables&rdquo; tab (and ensure Build Pull Requests is &lsquo;Off&rsquo;)</li>
<li>Create a new environment variable called <code>GH_TOKEN</code></li>
<li>In the Value field, paste in your token, being sure to remove any trailing whitespace</li>
<li>Ensure &ldquo;Display value in build logs&rdquo; is Off</li>
</ol>


<p>Once created, you&rsquo;re all set! <code>GH_TOKEN</code> will now be available to your <strong>deploy.sh</strong> script.</p>

<h2>Testing it out</h2>

<p>You should be ready to test your deployment. Commit any changes you have to your repository
and you should start seeing the build output once it starts. If there are any errors, now
you can fix them until your build passes.</p>

<p>Happy deploying!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
