<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Chrome | Kamranicus]]></title>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/categories/chrome/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-05T02:20:46+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://kamranicus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kamran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knockout.js Binding Report for Performance Tuning]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/25/knockout-binding-report/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-25T10:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/25/knockout-binding-report</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I use a lot of <a href="http://knockoutjs.com">Knockout.js</a> on <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com">Keep Track of My Games</a>. I love Knockout but sometimes it makes it difficult to understand what&rsquo;s slowing my page down.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>For the game list, there&rsquo;s a lot of binding going on because I have to bind not only the list of games but also the toolbar.</p>

<p><img src="http://41.media.tumblr.com/fefa8f95951ed13a2f4d22e758bb807b/tumblr_inline_nonu62Tr1J1qlpzxk_540.png" alt="KTOMG list" /></p>

<p>Before I deploy the newest update (shown above), I&rsquo;d prefer it if the list binding performance was better than it is now. Currently there&rsquo;s a visible block on the UI thread when returning results from the API, about 500-1000ms. <strong>This is unacceptable.</strong></p>

<p>A quick Google search did not yield anything regarding a &ldquo;real&rdquo; performance tool for Knockout. What I would love is an extension that would overlay performance statistics over the UI of my app after binding is complete. This way I could visualize and easily pinpoint what bindings are causing performance issues.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve made a small step towards that dream by creating a simple reporting script that outputs a &ldquo;binding report&rdquo; to the Chrome console:</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7795861/5a10389a-02d9-11e5-9462-056fa9e4da18.png" alt="Binding report" /></p>

<p>The report displays the total duration of the binding process (which is all bindings that occur after a 500ms wait time) as well as the top binding according to total duration.</p>

<p>It also displays each binding summary in a table (<code>console.table</code>). You can drill-down by expanding the array entries underneath the table (sorted by duration).</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7795969/8fb1c828-02da-11e5-8b81-fe88f466812e.png" alt="Drill-down" /></p>

<p>The script works by wrapping all the binding handlers (even custom ones) in a wrapper function that calculates the duration of the call to <code>init</code> or <code>update</code>. You just need to include it after your custom binding handlers and before the <code>applyBindings</code> call.</p>

<p>The script requires <a href="http://underscorejs.org">Underscore</a> and Google Chrome. Here&rsquo;s the gist:</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/kamranayub/65399fa247a6c182bc65.js"></script>


<p>As you can see in my own performance report, I have some work to do to fix my <code>if</code> bindings. It doesn&rsquo;t exactly pinpoint the problem binding, but it gets me a step closer to understanding what&rsquo;s going on.</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7796086/f407dc76-02db-11e5-90e7-b89613408174.png" alt="Uh oh" /></p>

<p>Now if you&rsquo;ll execuse me, I&rsquo;ve got some work to do.</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> Using this little script, I was able to get down to &lt;150ms from 600-900ms (and this is a slow laptop). This is much more acceptable for a release this week!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use a Separate Chrome Profile to Manage Your Apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/21/chrome-multi-user/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-21T13:45:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/21/chrome-multi-user</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re an app or site developer, you&rsquo;ve probably got a bunch of
tabs or bookmarks for your dashboards, social network accounts,
blog, and more. For <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com">Keep Track of My Games</a>,
I have UserVoice, Azure, RavenDB, social profiles, etc. that I
need to manage and track (haha).</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>It can be a chore to manage all of this easily but I have a tip.
A little while back Chrome <a href="https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/2364824?hl=en">introduced a new feature</a> that lets
you switch between multiple profiles super easily. I use it
for me and my wife, since she has a Google account and goes
to knitting sites and does whatever she likes doing&mdash;I don&rsquo;t want that filth in <em>my</em> Chrome instance! :)</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7749041/784a45e2-ffca-11e4-8a5f-ce5d1c445d4e.png" alt="Chrome user switcher is in the corner" /></p>

<p>The user switcher is in the top-right of Chrome, shown above. You can single-click to bring up a modal or right-click to quickly switch.
Chrome profiles are kept separate, with their own settings, extensions,
and bookmarks. This keeps tabs and work separated neatly and creates a
so-called &ldquo;separation of concerns&rdquo; for your browsing.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the rub: A full Chrome user is tied to a Google account. I don&rsquo;t want to create a separate Google account just for KTOMG.
The Google+, YouTube, email, etc. is all linked to my primary Google Account.
The issue is, Chrome will not let more than one
Google account exist on a single PC. So how can we take advantage of the profile separation but still
keep my primary Google account?</p>

<p>The answer is: we&rsquo;ll create a
<a href="https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/3463947">Supervised User Account</a>. Did you notice I said &ldquo;full user&rdquo; before?
A SUA is just a lower privilege profile (meant for children) that you can
control via your primary Google account. BUT, if you <strong>don&rsquo;t restrict anything</strong>,
it&rsquo;ll just be like a &ldquo;full&rdquo; profile!</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll follow the instructions above in the Google help article:</p>

<ol>
<li>Under your Chrome profile, go to Settings</li>
<li>Scroll down to Users</li>
<li>Click &ldquo;Add User&rdquo; and enter your app&rsquo;s name and avatar for a picture</li>
<li>Click &ldquo;Control and view websites this person visits from [your Google account]&rdquo;</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7749183/8dd90398-ffcb-11e4-8f8a-095f4a2e4beb.png" alt="Supervised user" /></p>

<p>Now you&rsquo;ve made a &ldquo;supervised&rdquo; app account managed by your main Google one. Nice! You can set up all your tabs as you want, <del>extensions with any
specific accounts (TweetDeck)</del>, and pinned dashboard tabs, all within a separate context from your primary Chrome profile. <strong>Update:</strong> It appears, after I tried, that SUA&rsquo;s cannot use extensions. There&rsquo;s an <a href="https://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=354178">open issue</a> for it, so hopefully whitelist ability will be added soon.</p>

<p>For example, here&rsquo;s what <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com">Keep Track of My Games</a>
looks like in its own Chrome profile:</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7749251/1de36eb0-ffcc-11e4-8be9-fa78b45a69da.png" alt="KTOMG profile" /></p>

<p>And the full experience:</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7749724/e2d07ed6-ffcf-11e4-93cd-f307718c2c82.png" alt="KTOMG browser" /></p>

<p>When you&rsquo;re the only one managing a bunch of apps, this
is a real productivity booster. You could even go as far as
creating separate profiles for each environment, if you like. Hell, this doesn&rsquo;t have to be for apps, it could be for whatever browsing contexts you want to separate.</p>

<p>Just make sure you have enough RAM because Chrome will
suck it all up.</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7749876/db3a810c-ffd0-11e4-8a35-5d96e41b874f.png" alt="Task manager" /></p>

<p>Dumb puny laptop.</p>

<p>Hope this helps! Happy managing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
