<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Javascript | Kamranicus]]></title>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/categories/javascript/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-06T17:43:52+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://kamranicus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kamran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Behind the Major Update to Keep Track of My Games]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/30/ktomg-update/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-30T22:13:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/30/ktomg-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7899619/b3154994-072a-11e5-8da1-b9a9703a8b57.png" alt="My profile" /></p>

<p>Today I just pushed a <strong>major</strong> update to <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com">KTOMG</a>. <em>Psst, you should join!</em></p>

<p>You can <a href="http://blog.keeptrackofmygames.com/post/120264549011/updates-for-may-2015">reference the blog post</a> for details on features but on the technical side I&rsquo;m pretty proud because I got to implement a bunch of new tech that I&rsquo;ve been wanting to learn properly.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h2>At a glance</h2>

<p>The site is built using <a href="http://getbootstrap.com">Bootstrap</a>, <a href="http://lesscss.org">LESS</a>, and <a href="http://knockoutjs.com">Knockout.js</a>. It is totally responsive and yes, every feature is available on every view. I don&rsquo;t yet have offline mode or some more app-y things like local storage quite yet but it&rsquo;s on my to-do list. By far the hardest thing to make responsive was the list view but using Flexbox and toolbar configurations, it&rsquo;s manageable. It could always be simpler though, my work is never done.</p>

<h2>CSS3 Flexbox</h2>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7899652/94500830-072c-11e5-8656-59fb097ecf36.png" alt="Lists" /></p>

<p>The list view is using <a href="https://css-tricks.com/snippets/css/a-guide-to-flexbox/">CSS3 Flexbox</a> with <code>display: table</code> fallback w/JavaScript. A Flexbox grid is perfect for a modern responsive app, which KTOMG is. It scales down to mobile fine (and if you don&rsquo;t have Flexbox or if the fallback fails, the worst you get is a stacked list). For different breakpoints I customize the flex basis of the items to create 1-3 column layouts. The homepage will soon use Flexbox as soon as I get to it (right now it&rsquo;s using <code>display: table</code> to maintain equal-height columns). All of the modern browsers support Flexbox and for those that don&rsquo;t, they just get a wrapping grid.</p>

<p>I also use Flexbox for any grid of games using table display as a fallback; this prevents me from needing to have fixed column sizes for different screen sizes so the games will just wrap as they need to.</p>

<p><strong>Aside:</strong> The box art image grid for the list is simply just the first four games in the list (dynamically updated, since the entire page uses Knockout) positioned using <code>background-size</code> and <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/CSS/Using_multiple_backgrounds">multiple backgrounds</a>. It uses a placeholder image repeated 4 times, in case the games are missing artwork and during loading.</p>

<p>Most of the CSS3/HTML5 stuff I have fallbacks by detecting features using <a href="http://modernizr.com/">Modernizr</a>.</p>

<h2>HTML5 Drag and Drop</h2>

<p>The other cool thing Flexbox gives you is some hot drag and drop action by allowing dynamic insertion of flex items:</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7899631/1b7db50c-072b-11e5-9977-49c7b6c3b176.gif" alt="Drag and drop" /></p>

<p>I wrote the drag and drop code in vanilla HTML5 Javascript, it wasn&rsquo;t too bad <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/HTML/Drag_and_drop">using MDN as a guide</a>. The fallback if that isn&rsquo;t supported is simply toolbar icons (which really is faster anyway for moving things far).</p>

<p>I admit I haven&rsquo;t tried a browser that <em>doesn&rsquo;t</em> support Flexbox but <em>does</em> support drag/drop, so that case might still need some tweaking.</p>

<h2>Hopscotch Tutorials</h2>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7899658/bda3d91e-072c-11e5-80ea-932d2f309681.png" alt="Tutorials" /></p>

<p>Since lists are pretty powerful, people might need some help remembering all the things they can do.</p>

<p>I use a modified version of <a href="http://linkedin.github.io/hopscotch">Hopscotch</a> for an introduction tutorial. I struggled at first to figure out how I wanted to do tutorials. I ended up just using a string array on every user that I fill in when they finish a tutorial, allowing for an infinite number of tutorials and everyone not seeing them by default. I keep a master list of valid tutorials on the server.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a simple solution that will let me add tutorials as I can make them. It took me a little finnagling, but I also got the tour working fine on small screens.</p>

<h2>Stats with Chart.js</h2>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7899666/222e5d5a-072d-11e5-9328-f52ae59c9e76.png" alt="Stats" /></p>

<p>I use <a href="http://www.chartjs.org/">Chart.js</a> for profile and list stats. The API is easy to use and easy to extend, as well as being sufficiently sexy. The stats I show right now are just the tip of the iceberg. I look forward to generating some cool charts later on (especially the Radar ones for comparisons).</p>

<p>Also, I apparently really like Action/Adventure and RPGs. But I knew that already, tell me something I don&rsquo;t know! Like maybe my &ldquo;burndown&rdquo; for finishing my backlog&hellip;</p>

<h2>I&rsquo;m excited</h2>

<p>I worked on this update all month as my wife will attest. I still have <a href="ktomg.uservoice.com/">plenty</a> to do but <a href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/21/5-things-for-6-months-abroad/">our vacation</a> is coming to an end. I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;ll be able to release such massive updates each month but this one definitely gets me closer to completing the vision I have. I&rsquo;m pretty excited! The updates are just in time for the big gaming conferences, if only I could get public lists out by the end of June&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knockout.js Binding Report for Performance Tuning]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/25/knockout-binding-report/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-25T10:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/25/knockout-binding-report</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I use a lot of <a href="http://knockoutjs.com">Knockout.js</a> on <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com">Keep Track of My Games</a>. I love Knockout but sometimes it makes it difficult to understand what&rsquo;s slowing my page down.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>For the game list, there&rsquo;s a lot of binding going on because I have to bind not only the list of games but also the toolbar.</p>

<p><img src="http://41.media.tumblr.com/fefa8f95951ed13a2f4d22e758bb807b/tumblr_inline_nonu62Tr1J1qlpzxk_540.png" alt="KTOMG list" /></p>

<p>Before I deploy the newest update (shown above), I&rsquo;d prefer it if the list binding performance was better than it is now. Currently there&rsquo;s a visible block on the UI thread when returning results from the API, about 500-1000ms. <strong>This is unacceptable.</strong></p>

<p>A quick Google search did not yield anything regarding a &ldquo;real&rdquo; performance tool for Knockout. What I would love is an extension that would overlay performance statistics over the UI of my app after binding is complete. This way I could visualize and easily pinpoint what bindings are causing performance issues.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve made a small step towards that dream by creating a simple reporting script that outputs a &ldquo;binding report&rdquo; to the Chrome console:</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7795861/5a10389a-02d9-11e5-9462-056fa9e4da18.png" alt="Binding report" /></p>

<p>The report displays the total duration of the binding process (which is all bindings that occur after a 500ms wait time) as well as the top binding according to total duration.</p>

<p>It also displays each binding summary in a table (<code>console.table</code>). You can drill-down by expanding the array entries underneath the table (sorted by duration).</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7795969/8fb1c828-02da-11e5-8b81-fe88f466812e.png" alt="Drill-down" /></p>

<p>The script works by wrapping all the binding handlers (even custom ones) in a wrapper function that calculates the duration of the call to <code>init</code> or <code>update</code>. You just need to include it after your custom binding handlers and before the <code>applyBindings</code> call.</p>

<p>The script requires <a href="http://underscorejs.org">Underscore</a> and Google Chrome. Here&rsquo;s the gist:</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/kamranayub/65399fa247a6c182bc65.js"></script>


<p>As you can see in my own performance report, I have some work to do to fix my <code>if</code> bindings. It doesn&rsquo;t exactly pinpoint the problem binding, but it gets me a step closer to understanding what&rsquo;s going on.</p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/563819/7796086/f407dc76-02db-11e5-90e7-b89613408174.png" alt="Uh oh" /></p>

<p>Now if you&rsquo;ll execuse me, I&rsquo;ve got some work to do.</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> Using this little script, I was able to get down to &lt;150ms from 600-900ms (and this is a slow laptop). This is much more acceptable for a release this week!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extending Knockout Observables to Sync With Address Bar]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/11/extending-knockout-with-urlsync/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-11T16:20:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/05/11/extending-knockout-with-urlsync</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I made a tiny Knockout extender called <code>urlSync</code> that syncs an observable with the URL.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>For <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com">Keep Track of My Games</a> I&rsquo;ve been adding filtering to the game library.
I&rsquo;m really proud of what I have, here&rsquo;s what it looks like in the UI:</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2015-05-11-filtering.png" alt="Filtering UI" /></p>

<p>A modal allows the user to drill down and pick what filters to apply, the modal updates to show what filters are applied and what&rsquo;s available with the current resultset.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2015-05-11-filtering-modal.png" alt="Filtering Modal" /></p>

<p>When you&rsquo;re outside the modal, I show any filters being applied allowing one-click removal or toggling the filtering method between AND/OR.</p>

<p>To make it easy to serialize/deserialize filters, I created a custom filtering expression that is pretty standard around town:</p>

<pre><code>{facetName}:{facetValue},{facetValue},...|...
</code></pre>

<p>For example, representing the screenshot above, the filtering expression would be:</p>

<pre><code>Lists:6|Status:8|My+Platforms:1
</code></pre>

<p>If you muck with the expression, there shouldn&rsquo;t be any issues. Facets are validated against whatever the original unfiltered resultset is, so you cannot add arbitrary expressions&mdash;if you do, they will not show up in the server response. Strings are special because potentially they can include characters used to parse the expression, the simplest way to deal with it is by encoding them and then decoding the value.</p>

<pre><code>Tags:my%20awesome%2ctag,tag2|Status:4
</code></pre>

<p>Now, I wanted to talk about the filtering expression because it makes it really easy to do a bunch of things:</p>

<ol>
<li>Reading/writing from querystring or hash</li>
<li>Create a command textbox that can parse and autocomplete expressions</li>
<li>Allow the user to save &ldquo;views&rdquo; of their games</li>
</ol>


<p>Items 2 and 3 might be on the agenda for some later date but item 1 is required for being able to create pre-filtered routes or create links. Since the library is loaded through Knockout and Web API, we need to be able to pass any filter or parameters when the page is loaded and also keep track of what the current values are for filtering.</p>

<p>To achieve this, I created a really simple <a href="http://knockoutjs.com/documentation/extenders.html">Knockout Extender</a> called <strong>urlSync.</strong> All it does is initially load an observable from the hash (if found) or the querystring (if found). Then it observes the observable and keeps the <code>window.location.hash</code> updated.</p>

<p>This could easily be extended to use <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/API/DOM/Manipulating_the_browser_history">HTML5 <code>pushState</code></a>, if you wished. For now, managing the hash is &ldquo;good enough&rdquo; for my use case.</p>

<p>Here is a Gist of the extender:</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/kamranayub/3feba45dd2da3262b872.js"></script>


<p>It depends on <a href="http://medialize.github.io/URI.js">URI.js</a> and the <a href="http://medialize.github.io/URI.js/docs.html#fragment-abuse">URI.fragmentQuery</a> component. It also uses <a href="http://underscorejs.org">Underscore.js</a>, but that&rsquo;s just because I have it in my project already.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s really simple to use, for example here&rsquo;s a snippet from my collection view model:</p>

<p>```
// Flattened facets
ViewModel.facets = ko.observableArray([]);</p>

<p>// Selected (applied) facets
ViewModel.selectedFacets = ko.observableArray([]).extend({</p>

<pre><code>urlSync: {
    param: "filterBy",
    read: function(value) {
       return kt.utils.facetsFromString(value, ViewModel.facets);
    },
    write: kt.utils.facetsToString
}
</code></pre>

<p>});</p>

<p>// Filter AND toggle
ViewModel.filterAnd = ko.observable(false).extend({ urlSync: &ldquo;filterAnd&rdquo; });
```</p>

<p>As you can see, the extender allows you to intercept read/write so you can perform any custom transformations (e.g. filtering objects to/from string). Because we&rsquo;re deserializing from a string and because the <code>checkedValue</code> binding is by reference, I pass in the existing facets collection to my utility, in order to preserve object references when required. On initial page load, this isn&rsquo;t required as the games haven&rsquo;t been fetched from the API yet. Once they are, my fetch method updates the observables. I could also modify the way I handle binding the checkboxes but this works.</p>

<p>The <code>urlSync</code> extender will then bind the observable values to the URL like this:</p>

<pre><code>users/kamran.ayub/lists/all#?
    sortBy=Name&amp;
    filterAnd=true&amp;
    filterBy=Status%3A8%7CLists%3A6%7CMy+Platforms%3A1
</code></pre>

<p>Since the extender can also fallback to reading from the querystring, we can create URLs that filter a user&rsquo;s collection:</p>

<pre><code>users/somebody/lists/all?filterBy=Platforms:2,5,40
</code></pre>

<p>Pretty neat and now allows anyone to copy/paste the URL and preserve any needed filtering state!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Triggering a Travis Build Programmatically]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/03/29/triggering-a-travis-build-programmatically/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-29T22:45:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/03/29/triggering-a-travis-build-programmatically</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For <a href="http://excaliburjs.com">Exalibur.js</a> we wanted to be able to keep our <code>master</code> branch documentation up-to-date on the website. The website is built using <a href="http://assemble.io">Assemble.io</a> and GitHub pages and <a href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/02/26/continuous-deployment-with-travis-ci/">after successfully automating my blog</a>, naturally I turned to <a href="http://travis-ci.org">Travis CI</a> to set up automated documentation generation.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>Travis normally sets up a hook in your GitHub repository to automatically trigger a build after you push a commit (or pull request). This is real nice but unfortunately that&rsquo;s where it stops. If you want to trigger a build <strong>for another repository</strong>, you have to do it manually.</p>

<p>I asked Travis about this and their response is promising (Twitter can be nice sometimes):</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/kamranayub">@kamranayub</a> it&#39;s on the roadmap, and hopefully landing soon &lt;3</p>&mdash; Travis CI (@travisci) <a href="https://twitter.com/travisci/status/582311038772723713">March 29, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://kamranicus.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Until that time, though, something has to be done.</p>

<p>One approach I saw was a <a href="https://github.com/metaodi/travis-ping">small Ruby script</a> to forge a webhook POST message. This is actually a nice idea but since Excalibur uses Node to build, I needed something else and didn&rsquo;t want to port it over.</p>

<p>Instead I borrowed some code from <a href="https://github.com/patrickkettner/travis-ping">@patrickketner</a> that uses the <a href="https://github.com/pwmckenna/node-travis-ci">node-travis-ci</a> npm package to submit a build through the public API. I modified Patrick&rsquo;s code since I need to use GitHub personal access tokens like I did <a href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/02/26/continuous-deployment-with-travis-ci/">previously</a>.</p>

<p>You still need to follow the same steps to set up the <code>GH_TOKEN</code> environment variable but once you do, all you have to do is execute this Node.js script (changing the <code>repo</code>).</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/kamranayub/88f963a9ac3d5bf6114d.js"></script>


<p>So for example, in your <code>.travis.yml</code> file, you just need:</p>

<p><code>
install:
  - npm install travis-ci
after_success:
  - node trigger-build.js
</code></p>

<p>All set. Now when you commit to one repository, you can trigger a build for another one. This allows us to automatically <a href="http://excaliburjs.com/docs/api/edge">keep our docs up-to-date</a> with whatever <code>master</code> has.</p>

<p>You can <a href="https://github.com/excaliburjs/Excalibur/blob/master/deploy-docs.js">reference Excalibur</a> to see how we execute the script. Additionally, you can reference <a href="https://github.com/excaliburjs/excaliburjs.github.io/blob/site/.travis.yml">excaliburjs.com&rsquo;s Travis configuration</a> to see how we use <a href="http://typedoc.io">TypeDoc</a> to generate documentation for the latest version of <code>master</code>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
