<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Azure | Kamranicus]]></title>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/categories/azure/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-02T22:56:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://kamranicus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kamran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Azure CDN Origin Pull With Cassette]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/10/10/azure-cdn-cassette/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-10T00:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/10/10/azure-cdn-cassette</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the October update for <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com">Keep Track of My Games</a> I wanted to offload my web assets to a CDN. Since I&rsquo;m already using <a href="http://azure.com">Microsoft Azure</a> to host the site, I decided to use <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/cdn/">Azure CDN</a>.</p>

<p>I set it up for &ldquo;Origin Pull&rdquo; which means that instead of uploading my assets to the CDN (Azure Blob storage), you request a file from the CDN and Azure will go and get it from your website and then cache it on their servers.</p>

<p>So as an example:</p>

<p><code>
User requests http://az888888.vo.msecnd.net/stylesheets/foo.png
|
|
CDN: have I cached "stylesheets/foo.png?"
  Yes: Serve content from edge cache (closest to user)
  No: Request http://yourwebsites.com/stylesheets/foo.png and serve
</code></p>

<p>You can read more about <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/articles/cdn-create-new-endpoint/">how to set up origin pull in Azure CDN</a>. In my case, I used &ldquo;Custom Origin&rdquo; of &ldquo;<a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com">http://keeptrackofmygames.com</a>&rdquo;.</p>

<h2>Using CDN with Cassette</h2>

<p>I use the .NET library <a href="http://getcassette.com">Cassette</a> for bundling &amp; minification for KTOMG&mdash;when I started KTOMG there was no Microsoft provided option and Cassette has been really stable.</p>

<p>It works pretty much as you&rsquo;d expect:</p>

<ul>
<li>Define &ldquo;bundles&rdquo; which are sets of scripts/stylesheets</li>
<li>Render bundles onto page(s)</li>
<li>If debug mode, render individually otherwise minify and concatenate</li>
</ul>


<p>By default, Cassette will render URLs like this in your source code:</p>

<p>In debug mode:</p>

<p>```
Bundle: ~/Content/core</p>

<ul>
<li>/cassette.axd/asset/Content/bootstrap.css?hash</li>
<li>/cassette.axd/asset/Content/site.css?hash</li>
<li>/cassette.axd/asset/Content/app.css?hash
```</li>
</ul>


<p>And in production:</p>

<p><code>
/cassette.axd/stylesheet/{hash}/Content/core
</code></p>

<p>But if we want to serve assets over the CDN, we need to plug in our special CDN URL prefix&mdash;not only for script/stylesheet references but also references to images <em>in</em> those files.</p>

<p>Luckily, Cassette provides a facility to modify generated URLs by letting you register a <code>IUrlGenerator</code>. Here&rsquo;s my full implementation of this for my CDN:</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/kamranayub/2da4ccfec3e7812c8367.js"></script>


<p>As you can see, I register a custom <code>IUrlGenerator</code> and a custom <code>IUrlModifier</code>. The default <code>IUrlModifider</code> is Cassette&rsquo;s <code>VirtualDirectoryPrepender</code> and it just prepends &ldquo;/&rdquo; to the beginning of every URL but in our case we want to conditionally prepend the Azure CDN endpoint in production.</p>

<p>In production, this will produce the following output:</p>

<p><code>
https://az99999.vo.msecnd.net/cassette.axd/stylesheet/{hash}/Content/core
</code></p>

<p>To allow local debugging and CDN in production I just use an app setting in the web.config. In Azure, I also add an application setting (<code>CdnUrl</code>) through the portal in my production slot with the correct CDN URL and voila&mdash;all my assets will now be served over CDN.</p>

<h3>Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Azure CDN does not yet support HTTPS for custom origin domains. So if you want to serve content over <a href="http://static.yoursite.com">http://static.yoursite.com</a> you can&rsquo;t serve it over HTTPS because Azure doesn&rsquo;t allow you to upload or set a SSL certificate to use and insteads uses their own certificate which is not valid for your domain. <a href="http://feedback.azure.com/forums/169397-cdn/suggestions/1332683-allow-https-for-custom-cdn-domain-names">Vote up the UserVoice issue</a> on this.</p></li>
<li><p>Azure CDN origin pull does not seem to respect <code>Cache-Control: private</code> HTTP header. For example, by default MVC serves pages with private cache control which means browsers won&rsquo;t cache that page and neither <em>should</em> Azure CDN&mdash;but it does anyway. In my case, I really don&rsquo;t want a true mirror of my site, I just wants assets served over CDN and Cassette sets <code>Cache-Control: public</code> on them automatically. <a href="http://feedback.azure.com/forums/169397-cdn/suggestions/10148280-respect-cache-control-private-for-origin-pull">You can upvote my feature request on UserVoice</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>I am choosing <strong>not</strong> to point my entire domain to the CDN. Some folks choose to serve their entire site over the CDN which is definitely something you can do. However, in my case, I didn&rsquo;t want to do that. If you instead chose to point your domain to the CDN endpoint, you don&rsquo;t need to do any of this&mdash;<strong>everything</strong> will be served over the CDN.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting WebSockets to Work on Windows Azure]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2014/02/09/websockets-on-windows-azure/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-09T03:52:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2014/02/09/websockets-on-windows-azure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was banging my head against the wall for the past hour or so wondering why I was falling back to XHR polling when I deployed my Node.js application to Azure. I&rsquo;m using socket.io and everything looks like it&rsquo;s in order, works locally, etc. It was failing with a WebSocket handshake error.</p>

<p>What I saw in the Chrome developer console was something like:</p>

<pre><code>Error during WebSocket handshake: Unexpected response code: 502
</code></pre>

<p>In my Azure Node.js console (<code>azure site log tail SITENAME</code>), I was seeing <code>EPIPE</code> errors.</p>

<p>It turns out, this little tidbit from the <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazure/archive/2013/11/14/introduction-to-websockets-on-windows-azure-web-sites.aspx">original Windows Azure blog post</a> on Web Sockets did the trick.</p>

<p>Modify your <strong>web.config</strong> and add:</p>

<pre><code>&lt;webSocket enabled="false" /&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>To your <code>system.webServer</code> configuration. Also, another good point in that blog post is to use SSL, since you get SSL for free with a <code>*.azurewebsites.net</code> site.</p>

<p>Hope this helps someone else out there. This should be added to the <a href="http://www.windowsazure.com/en-us/documentation/articles/web-sites-nodejs-chat-app-socketio/">official Azure tutorial</a> on using web sockets with Node.js.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
