<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: SpecFlow | Kamranicus]]></title>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/categories/specflow/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-24T01:16:02+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://kamranicus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kamran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impersonating a User During Automated Testing Scenarios]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/11/06/impersonating-during-testing/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-06T16:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2015/11/06/impersonating-during-testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m starting to introduce privacy controls to <a href="http://keeptrackofmygames.com">Keep Track of My Games</a> and I ran into the following scenario when writing my tests:</p>

<p>```
Scenario: Anonymous user should be able to view a public custom list</p>

<pre><code>Given a user has a list
And a user's list is public
When I request access to the list
Then I have read-only access
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>In this context, <strong>I</strong> am the anonymous user. This is the exact <a href="http://www.specflow.org/">SpecFlow</a> scenario I wrote. Do you know why I may have run into issues?</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s look at the first two steps:</p>

<p>```c#
[Given(@&ldquo;a user has a list&rdquo;)]
public void GivenAUserHasAList() {</p>

<pre><code>_listResult = _context.ListService.CreateList(_newList)
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>[Given(@&ldquo;a user&rsquo;s list is public&rdquo;)]
public void GivenAUsersListIsPublic() {
  <em>privacySettings.Level = PrivacyLevel.Public;
  </em>context.ListService.UpdateListPrivacy(<em>listResult.Id, </em>privacySettings);
}
```</p>

<p>Why would this cause a problem with my given scenario?</p>

<ol>
<li>In the first step, I&rsquo;m creating a new list.</li>
<li>In the second step, I&rsquo;m taking the new list I just made from the first step and updating the privacy settings on it.</li>
</ol>


<p>The problem is that my service assumes the context is an authenticated user and will apply changes to the <strong>current user&rsquo;s</strong> list. Well, since I did not call my login helpers before these two steps, I am in an anonymous context so the service calls fail. That&rsquo;s good! But how can I tell my steps to call a service method <em>on behalf</em> of another user without having <em>every</em> step use the current user context?</p>

<p>You might say I should just create a new method that accepts a username and refactor my methods. I <em>could</em> do that but not only is my entire service designed around the current user context, my service layer is essentially the interface of my public API. I would never allow one user to create a list for another user (unless that was a feature). So the same way I wouldn&rsquo;t expose an API method to do something on behalf of someone, I won&rsquo;t add a public method in my service layer to do the same. I could choose to make the method private or internal and grant access to the assembly for testing&mdash;true, I <em>could</em> but that seems like a workaround where I need to expose special functionality just for testing.</p>

<p>The approach I ended up doing was simpler and more elegant and leveraged an existing pattern I was relying on: injecting an <code>IUserContext</code> into my service layer like this:</p>

<p><code>c#
public ListService(IUserContext userContext) {
  _userContext = userContext;
}
</code></p>

<p>This is using standard dependency injection (Ninject, in my case) to inject a context for the current user. That context gets created and maintained outside this class, so it doesn&rsquo;t care who provided it or where it came from, it just uses it to determine business logic.</p>

<p>So since I&rsquo;m already injecting the current user context and mocking it in my tests, why not simply swap out the context when I need to?</p>

<h2>Creating an impersonation context</h2>

<p>That&rsquo;s what I ended up doing. Here&rsquo;s my implementation of a <code>TestingImpersonationContext</code> (<a href="https://gist.github.com/kamranayub/9654d6581fbcf63cf481">https://gist.github.com/kamranayub/9654d6581fbcf63cf481</a>):</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/kamranayub/9654d6581fbcf63cf481.js"></script>


<p>It should be clear what&rsquo;s happening but let me explain further. Specifically in SpecFlow you can inject a context into your testing steps like so:</p>

<p>```c#
public class StepBase : TechTalk.SpecFlow.Steps {</p>

<pre><code>protected TestingContext _context;
public StepBase(TestingContext context)
{
    _context = context;
}
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>As long as your step classes inherit that <code>StepBase</code>, you have access to a context. All I did was build a method off that context that swapped out my existing dependency that was injected for <code>IUserContext</code> with a temporary context that impersonated the requested user. Once it is disposed, it restores the original context. Easy as pie!</p>

<p>If you are <strong>not</strong> using SpecFlow which is probably the case, don&rsquo;t fret&mdash;all you really need is a class or helper method that you can access in your test classes. However you want to achieve that is up to you. Create a base class, don&rsquo;t even bother with dependency injection, etc. This is entirely doable without DI but since my app relies on it I also leverage it during testing.</p>

<p>Now given we have an impersonation context helper, here&rsquo;s how our two testing steps have changed:</p>

<p>```c#
[Given(@&ldquo;a user has a list&rdquo;)]
public void GivenAUserHasAList() {
  using (_context.Impersonate(&ldquo;user&rdquo;) {</p>

<pre><code>_listResult = _context.ListService.CreateList(_newList);
</code></pre>

<p>  }
}</p>

<p>[Given(@&ldquo;a user&rsquo;s list is public&rdquo;)]
public void GivenAUsersListIsPublic() {</p>

<pre><code>using (_context.Impersonate("user"))
{
    _privacySettings.Level = PrivacyLevel.Public;
    _context.ListService.UpdateListPrivacy(_listResult.Id, _privacySettings);
}
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>I could even update my scenario to be specific about <strong>who&rsquo;s list</strong> I&rsquo;m accessing (so it&rsquo;s not ambiguous between logged in user vs. another user) but since I only have two users in my testing context, it doesn&rsquo;t really matter.</p>

<p>Now for the test results:</p>

<p><code>
Given a user has a list
-&gt; done: ListSteps.GivenAUserHasAList() (0.2s)
And a user's list is public
-&gt; done: ListSteps.GivenAUsersListIsPublic() (0.0s)
When I request access to the list
-&gt; done: ListSteps.WhenIRequestAccessToTheList() (0.1s)
Then I have read-only access
-&gt; done: ListSteps.ThenIHaveReadAccess() (0.0s)
</code></p>

<p>The tests are green and now I&rsquo;m a happy coder. By the way, if you aren&rsquo;t using <a href="http://specflow.org">SpecFlow</a> for .NET you should consider it, I love it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
