<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Conferences | Kamranicus]]></title>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/categories/conferences/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kamranicus.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-11T01:04:25+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://kamranicus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kamran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[See You at Build 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/2016/03/11/attending-build-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-11T00:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kamranicus.com/blog/2016/03/11/attending-build-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love attending conferences. At the end of January me and some friends <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BBJQ-PTuIzZ">attended PAX South</a> in San Antonio and it was a blast (not for work). A gaming convention has a different air than a developer conference. There&rsquo;s a certain energy and it&rsquo;s very motivating being around fellow developers, learning new tech, and seeing what&rsquo;s new. I&rsquo;ve attended Build several times in the past and it&rsquo;s always been fun&mdash;especially <a href="http://kamranicus.com/blog/posts/7/mix-11-day-2-kinects-celebrities-kings-and-clubbin/">when you meet coding &ldquo;celebs&rdquo;</a>. Usually I take my wife even though she doesn&rsquo;t attend the conference, we will typically stay longer. This year, not only will she be joining but our friend will be coming as well&mdash;both of them will be traipsing around San Francisco while I and a few coworkers will attend the conference. My partners in crime, <a href="http://twitter.com/erikonarheim">Erik</a> &amp; <a href="http://twitter.com/alangrgic">Alan</a>, will be joining me so it&rsquo;ll be a <em>ton</em> of fun (yes, we all work together and yes we <em>just</em> went to PAX together). Going to a conference is fun, going to a conference <em>with your friends</em> is even more fun.</p>

<p>After Build we&rsquo;ll be leaving my coworkers behind and we&rsquo;ll be flying up to Portland to explore the area. I&rsquo;ve been to downtown Seattle for PAX Prime before but I&rsquo;ve only been in the surrounding area once when I was a teenager and I always thought it was beautiful. My wife never has been to the Pacific northwest so we thought it&rsquo;d be fun to spend a few days extra and drive around. We&rsquo;re all looking forward to it.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re at Build and you follow me, be sure to <a href="http://twitter.com/kamranayub">send me a tweet</a> and we&rsquo;ll meet up!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
